A Guide to the Public Guard records of the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts, 1801-1868
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Public Guard records of the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts, 1801-1868
The Library of Virginia
APA 199
2.2. cu. ft. (8 boxes)
Virginia. Auditor of Public Accounts.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred prior to 1913.
Biographical Information
The public guard was established in 1802 for the protection of public property in Richmond. From 1802 through 1822 the guard was quartered on Capitol Square in the Bell Tower; after 1822 the guard was stationed at the Virginia Manufactory of Arms. The public guard was abolished in 1869.
Scope and Content
Records, 1801-1868, including accounts, muster and payrolls, provision returns, receipt rolls, and vouchers of the Public Guard. The accounts and vouchers were for clothing (hats, shirts, shoes, vests), thread and cloth, monies paid to the guard, cords of wood, rations of spirits, food (tea, lamb, chicken, sugar, oysters, lamb, beef, veal), payments to the hospital to care for sick guards,
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series by size and then chronologically within each series.
Contents List
- Series I: Accounts and vouchers
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1801 March-May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1801 June-August (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1806, 1808 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1812 April-May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1812 June-September (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1812 October-December (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1813 January-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1813 July-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Muster rolls and reports, 1813-1815 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1819 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1858, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Accounts and vouchers, 1865-1866 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series II: Accounts, muster and pay rolls [oversize]
  - Account of rations, spirits, quartermaster and hospital stores furnished, 1801 May 23-June 22 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Account of rations, spirits, quartermaster and hospital stores furnished, 1801 June 23-July 22 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Account of rations, spirits, quartermaster and hospital stores furnished, 1801 July 23-August 22 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Account of rations, spirits, quartermaster and hospital stores furnished, 1806 February (Drawer 3, Folder 1)
  - Muster rolls, 1801 April-May (Folder 2)
  - Muster rolls, 1801 June-July (Folder 2)
  - Pay rolls, 1801 February-April (Folder 2)
  - Pay rolls, 1801 April-May (Folder 2)
  - Pay rolls, 1801 June-July (Folder 2)
  - Pay rolls, 1812 April-December (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pay rolls, 1813 January-December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Muster rolls, 1815 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pay rolls, 1825 September-1826 January (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Receipt rolls, 1826 February-July (Folder 6)
  - Muster rolls, 1826 June-July (Folder 6)
  - Pay rolls, 1826 June-July (Folder 6)
  - Receipt rolls, 1858 August-September (Folder 7)
  - Receipt rolls, 1862 October-November (Folder 7)
  - Receipt rolls, 1863 (Folder 7)
  - Muster rolls, 1864 August-1865 January (Folder 8)
  - Pay rolls, 1864 August-December (Folder 8)
  - Receipt rolls, 1864 June-November (Folder 8)
  - Muster rolls, 1865 February-March (Folder 9)
  - Pay rolls, 1864 December-1865 March (Folder 9)
  - Receipt rolls, 1864 December-1865 May (Folder 9)